AYANLEYE S. OLUWATOYIN

APPLICATION SECURITY ENGINEER

■ ayanleyetoyin@outlook.com ② nullcell8822.github.io 📞 +2349020674624 🔍 Lagos, Nigeria

Summary

I am a young professional skilled in scripting, web application security, network security, firmware development and embedded application development. Currently working on bug bounties and open-source web application code review and testing, developing an automation script for reconnaissance, vulnerability discovery, and testing. I am currently training on AWS Solutions Architecture and always learning using various platforms and reading up on the latest trends.

Skills

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES AND FRAMEWORKS: Python, C, C++, Bash, Yocto

TOOLSETS AND OS: Linux, Windows, GitHub, Git, Wireshark, Nessus, VMware, Metasploit, Burpsuite, Docker

HARDWARE: Reading Schematics, Circuit Prototyping, Referencing HW datasheets, Raspberry Pi, Arduino **TECHNICAL SKILLS:** Application Penetration Testing, Network Vulnerability Testing, Bug Bounty,

AWS Solutions Architecture

Projects

Internal Port Forwarding Script

- Bash script to be run on a compromised system within an internal network to scan and forward selected ports to a remote attacker via different means.
- Base functionality completed and currently being extended for other uses

Automated Network Domain Scanning Tool

- Custom Automated Scanner for Web and Networks. It works using modules and plugins to each module to extend functionality.
- It automates common manual Penetration Testing practices and is continuously developed using publicly available information and personal experiences.
- Current modules include Domain Recon for Bug Bounties and Network Automated Scanning and Exploit Suggestion.
- The project is still in early stages and as such the repo is still private.

Pentesting Environment Setup Tool

- Bash script for one line install of most penetration testing tools for Debian based Linux Distributions e.g. AWS VPS and Raspberry Pi 4 (64-bit)

Ardupilot Based Drone

- Constructed a drone using the ardupilot flight controller and adding a master microcontroller for autonomous control

Employment

Web Test on Insurance Company

Freelancer Dec. 2021 to Jan. 2022

- Discovered and exploited various critical vulnerabilities on the insurance company
- Chained vulnerabilities to get RCE on the server and took control over other websites running on the server
- Gained access to the database via SQLi

M4xH3dr00m Nigeria
Team Member July 2021 to Present

- Won CyberTalents Nationals CTF and America Business Council CTF

- Discovered and found a solution to Laravel Illuminate Validation RCE via an upload vulnerability

Linux Professional Institute Innovation Hub

Intern

Appleton Road, Ibadan Aug. 2021 to Jan. 2022

- AWS Solutions Architect Training
- Trained students in cybersecurity
- I served as technical support for hosted events

Vinsighte

Appleton Road, University of Ibadan, Ibadan

Embedded Software Developer

Oct. 2019 to Mar. 2020

- Successfully developed the prototype for reading glasses for the visually impaired

Education

University of Ibadan

Feb. 2017 to Nov. 2022

B.Sc Electrical and Electronics Engineering 2022

The International School Olabisi Onabanjo University, Ago-Iwoye

Trinity International College, Ofada

Sept. 2012 to July 2016 Sept. 2010 to July 2012

Volunteering

Google Developer Student Club - University of Ibadan \cdot Cybersecurity Lead

Ibadan, Nigeria

Trained fellow students who want to get into the field of Cybersecurity

IEEE-UISB · Embedded Team Lead

Oct. 2019 to Oct. 2021

Oct. 2021 to Present

Awards

University of Ibadan Worked on maze solving RC cars

 $Cyber\ Talents\cdot {\it Cyber\ Talents\ Nationals\ CTF\ -\ Nigeria\ 1st\ Place}$

Sept. 2021

Sept. 2021

- Cyber Talents' Annual CTF National for Nigeria to qualify for Africa and Middle-East Challenge

American Business Council · American Business Council Cybersecurity CTF 2nd Place

- A CTF hosted by The American Business Council Nigeria for Cybersecurity Professionals

CampusLabs with US Embassy · Hackathon Winner

Apr. 2019

A disability hackathon to find solutions to help people with various kinds of disabilities. My solution proposed a design for an autom

Hult Prize Foundation · Hult Prize

Oct. 2018

- Hult prize UI for creating jobs for 10,000 people withing the next 10 years.